ASHLEY E. NGUYEN

FULL-SCACK ENGINEER

Los Angeles, CA

HTML5 | CSS3 | GICHUB/GIC

Javascript | Python

EJS | React | Node.JS

EXPRESS | MONGODB

FLƏSK | SQL ALCHEMY SEQUELIZE | POSGGESQL

SKILLS

SIIMMARY

Full-stack engineer pivoting from 12 years of behavior analytic experience collecting & analyzing data and making data-driven decisions to solve problems, implement solutions, and audit success in the context of Human and Autism Services and graduate level education. Seeking an opportunity to apply these skills in the tech industry by building applications that produce measurable improvement in performance and quality of life.

PROJECTS

DJango

Virtual Beer Pong

HTML | CSS | JAVASCRIPT

Automated Stimulus Display and Data Collection (ASDDC)

REACT | SQL ALCHEMY FLASK | PYCHON

Leafy Ledger

EXPRESS | EJS NODE.JS | POSCGRESQL

certificates

General Assembly
LOS ANGELES (REMOCE)

December 2020

Software Engineering BOARD CERCIFIED BEHAVIOR ANALYSC

May 2016

Certificate#: 1-16-22669

EDUCATION

THE CHICAGO SCHOOL OF PROFESSIONAL PSYCHOLOGY

Ph.D. Psychology, Behavior Analysis Specialization

August 2017 - Present GPA: 4.0

M.S. Applied Behavior Analysis

October 2015

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

B.A. Psychology

May 2008

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

Instructional Associate

West Coast (Remote)

January 2021 - April 2021

smashflashtech@gmail.com

www.smashflashtech.com

(213) 290-3296

- O Facilitates acquisition of frontend & backend development technologies across two programming languages for a cohort of 30 students with 100% on track to graduate.
- O Audits lessons & provides feedback to students for 30+ pull requests per week.
- O Supports student project development using an Agile project management approach.

The Chicago School of Professional Psychology Adjunct Faculty

Los Angeles & Irvine, CA

August 2018 - October 2020

- O Established curriculum and associated experiential activities for Behavioral Assessments master level course used across three Southern CA campuses.
- O Led graduate students through hands-on application of behavioral technologies while providing instruction, modeling, constructive feedback, and performance evaluation across various Practicum skills & topics resulting in 100% pass rate.

Curriculum Development Collaborator

Chicago, IL (Remote)

August 2019 - April 2020

- O Developed curriculum and associated experiential activities for Behavioral Assessments bachelor level course for remote online instruction.
- O Audited course materials for final publication ensuring curriculum met educational standards and certification board requirements and ADA compliance leading to successful course publication by Fall 2020 semester.

Easterseals Southern California

Regional Trainer

Southern California Counties

May 2017 - September 2017

- O Analyzed complex skills and developed standardized training protocols enabling quality assurance competency checks for clinical and administrative performance.
- O Trained staff in crisis management and behavioral technologies using research-based methods leading to 100% pass rate.

Program Manager

Los Angeles, CA

June 2016 - May 2017

- Evaluated data, summarized results, and recommended treatment options to stakeholders leading to continuation, termination, or graduation of services.
- O Supervised staff performance, provided training, assessed morale, and coordinated team building meetings leading to 100% retention of direct supervisees.

Working with Autism, Inc. Behavior Intervention Implementer

Los Angeles, CA

January 2012 - May 2016

O Implemented protocols for skill acquisition, problem behavior reduction, and crisis management to increase social & adaptive engagement for children with autism.